#### ABHINAV ARORA

Fullerton, CA, 92831 | 657-217-7312 | abhinavaroraa14799@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/abhinavarora14799 | EPortfolio:www.abhinavarora.life|linkedin.com/in/abhinavarora14799

#### **SUMMARY**

Abhinav Arora is a Senior Computer Science major student at California State University Fullerton. An agile collaborative developer with strong problem-solving skills, and notable experience in Front End Development focused with MERN stack, Web-Applications Development, Full Stack Development, Unit Testing, Cloud Computing, and IT System Administration.

#### **EDUCATION**

California State University - Fullerton

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Current GPA - 3.31)

August 2018 - May 2022 Fullerton, California

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Proficient in JavaScript, Python, C++, PHP, Laravel, SQL, AWS, Vue, React, Salesforce, GIT, Java, C#, Java, .NET, Node, Kubernetes, and JSON.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineering Intern | Solar Insure Inc. | Costa Mesa, California

January 2022 - Present

- Designed and built web applications to connect data from RESTful APIs into Vue, and Laravel Customer Portal.
- Built and Integrated new features to the portal with viewing traffic in the 99th percentile (50th out of 10,000 SPA dashboards).
- Implemented custom Tailwind-CSS changes to the front-end which decreased the front-end Compilation time by 60%.
- Migrated entire codebase of the Project to AWS S3 bucket from Digital Ocean, which increased company's global outreach by 33%.
- Refactored Front-End of the application from Vue.Js to React framework, to update SDLC, and to develop mobile application using Native.

# JavaScript Developer | California State University Fullerton | Fullerton, California

September 2021 - January 2022

- Developed a custom web-portal to embed virtual agent-mentors for the Career Fair. AI Project.
- Leveraged the inbuilt React framework toolkit to create frontend features, and responsive user interface components.
- Optimized React components for maximum performance of the website and wrote front-end code for 3 different platform applications.

## Information Technology Intern | Sensorex | Garden Grove, California

August 2021 - December 2021

- Wrote custom HTML, PHP, CSS, and JavaScript, to add different features to online platform which resulted in boost to UX scores by 28%.
- Designed and refactored multiple user reactive pages, which Increased customer traffic by 50% (60,000 new site acquisitions since V2).
- Handled visual, responsive implementation of front-end features which resulted in a raise in dwell time by 30%.
- Implemented a solution to embed 10 dashboards of different products in 1 by redesigning data model.

## Student Software Developer | California State University Fullerton | Fullerton, California

March 2021 - Present

- Implemented interaction between frontend and backend using the ISON object at the University Data Center.
- Monitored all network processes to ensure the smooth flow of data across the network of almost 150 active CSUF Servers.
- Reduced deployment time by almost 100 seconds by developing bash scripts to automate build and deployment on Ubuntu servers.

### Associate Software Developer | EZ-Health Track | Foster City, California

August 2020 - December 2020

- Leveraged responsive web-frameworks, and prepared proper documentation to complete deliverables ahead of schedule.
- Developed UI pages using ISP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript technologies.

# Research Student Assistant | California State University Fullerton | Fullerton, California

June 2019 - August 2020

- Developed custom data models and algorithms to apply to data sets and Queries.
- Improved and evaluated data collection processes by assessing, streamlining, automating existing systems at the office of Assessment.

## Webmaster | California State University Fullerton | Fullerton, California

May 2019 - August 2019

- Established, and maintained web system and tested servers and operating systems for the Division of Administration and Finance.
- Updated and created webpages and maintained them up to mark with ATI compliance and maintained a healthy SDLC.

# Front End Development Intern| InfoSoft Technologies | New Delhi, India

July 2017 - January 2018

- Worked closely with backend engineers to seamlessly integrate with frontend systems using the JSON object.
- Performed bug fixes and code refactoring which allowed the technical debt to decrease by 32% within first two months.

## **BOARD POSITION**

### **ACM External Vice President**

May 2020 - May 2021

- Handled professional outreach tasks to build relationships with companies and planned professional events.
- Organized, managed, and created Project Jams, Interview practice workshops, and career workshops.
- Lead Product Tank Events which focused on networking events with Alumni working in the Product management roles.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• IBM - Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner.

August 2021 - Present

# **PERSONAL \ GROUP PROJECTS**

Pizza Radar

July 2021 – August 2021

- Designed a JavaScript React native Web-application that provides user with the list of nearest Pizza restaurants in the area.
- Implemented the Yelp API which allowed the program to Display over 1000 Pizza restaurants in the maximum radius of 100 miles of user.
   Google Maps API
   December 2018 January 2019
- Designed a Program (C++) which integrates Google Maps API hosted in Google's Servers.
- Converted a Physical mailing address to its corresponding geolocations using Geocoding API, also encoded Reverse, Elevation features.

  Chrome Speak

  November 2018– March 2019
- Collaborated and created an extension on Google Chrome named as Chrome Speak with Amazon Alexa.
- Added voice control feature for disabled support that assisted webpage navigation on Google Chrome.

### **AWARDS & ACCOLADES**

Gold Medals in Cyber Olympiad 2016 (State) and International Mathematics Olympiad 2017 (Regional).